<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ouer-throvv of an Irish rebell, in a late battaile: or The death of Sir Carey Adoughertie who murdred Sir George Paulet in Ireland; and for his rebellion hath his head now standing ouer Newgate in Dublin.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1608</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 15 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A08461</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 18786</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S106353</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99842071</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99842071</idno>
            <idno type="VID">6695</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A08461)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 6695)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 725:04)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Ouer-throvv of an Irish rebell, in a late battaile: or The death of Sir Carey Adoughertie who murdred Sir George Paulet in Ireland; and for his rebellion hath his head now standing ouer Newgate in Dublin.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[22] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[By G. Eld] for I. Wright, and are to be sold at his shop neere Christ Church gate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprinted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1608.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Printer's name from STC.</note>
                  <note>With woodcut title vignette.</note>
                  <note>Colophon reads: Dublin printed by Iohn Franckton, printer to the kings most excellent Maiestie, 1608.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A⁴(-A1) B-C⁴.</note>
                  <note>Considerable print show-through; some pages stained.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>O'Dogherty, Cahir, --  Sir, 1587-1608 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:6695:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:6695:1"/>
            <p>THE Ouer-throw of an Iriſh rebell, in a late battaile: Or The death of Sir <hi>Carey Adoughertie,</hi> who murdred <hi>Sir</hi> George Paulet <hi>in Ireland; and for his</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellion hath his head now ſtanding ouer Newgate in Dublin.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>depiction of Newgate prison, Dublin, with displayed heads of executed rebels</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>Imprinted at London for I. Wright, and are to be ſold at his ſhop neere Chriſt Church gate. 1608.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <gap reason="missing" extent="2 pages">
               <desc>〈2 pages missing〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:6695:2"/>
            <p>by them: Yea to ſuch a habit of Sauage tirany hath Rebellion brought that nation, that no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing hath beene or ſtill is pleaſing to a great part of them, but that which all ciuill kingdomes abhor, (as beeing their onely plague) and that is Ciuill Warre: Murders and Maſſacres and vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rores are to them as Muſick &amp; Banquets: bloud as the moſt delicate cups of wine: Thou needeſt not (O gallant country) to boaſt that no vene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous beaſt is bread within thee, for the hearts of thy diſobedient children are full of rancke poyſon: Thou haſt deſerued to bee called not one of the daughters of <hi>Britannia,</hi> but to bee re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iected as a baſtard: and albeit from time to time, ſhe hath beene vnto thee as a louing Nurſe and Mother, thou canſt not condemne her of vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kindeneſſe if ſhee proue vnto thee a ſtepdame. How many hundreds of thouſands of our Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh nation haue beene drowned in their owne bloud, ſluc'de out by thy treachery how many of our Nobility haue loſt their liues and beene confounded, whilſt in their duety and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>legiance they went about to enduce thee to ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uility, or to chaſtize thee for thy Stubburnnes? how many widowes haue bewailed the loſſe of their husbands, butcherd by thy rebellious peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple? how many ſonnes and daughters by thy meanes haue been left fatherleſſe? Yet if thou lookeſt backe (ô <hi>Ireland</hi>) either vpon the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunate reigne of thy late Queene and miſtreſſe
<pb facs="tcp:6695:2"/>
(of happy memory) or doeſt but number vp the daies of reſt which thy now royall ſoueraigne (our moſt gracious King) hath in his peacefull and bleſſed gouernment beſtowed vpon thee, thou canſt not chooſe but confeſſe, that (thy ill deſeruings beeing ſo many) thou haſt beene fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uorably dealt withall, in being not puniſhed ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the meaſure of thy offendings: thou haſt beene worthy to haue beene beaten with rods of Iron for thy vnrulineſſe, and to haue had fire the ſword playe the executioners vppon thee and thy nation for their ſtiff-necked rebel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion. But our Princes haue beene vnto thee in their correction as fathers are to children, when they puniſh them, yet nothing can win thee to goodneſſe or weane thee from thy bloudy and barbarous proceedings.</p>
            <p>But let vs leaue this ſtreame, and hoiſt vp ſailes in that ſea where our intent was at firſt to end our voiage. And that is to diſcouer the onſet and ouerthrow of a Rebell, or rather conductor of Rebells, Sir <hi>Carey Adougherty.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>You ſhall therefore vnderſtand, that Sir <hi>Carey Adoughertie,</hi> hauing with his bloudie aſſotiate <hi>(Fallin Reeah Mack Dauy)</hi> committed that inhu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maine murder vpon Sir <hi>George Paulet,</hi> and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers the inhabitantes of the towne of Derry, thought with the <hi>Tragicall Poet, Tutum eſſe ſce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leribus per ſcelus itur,</hi> that the onely buckler to defend villanies was to ioyne the army of more
<gap reason="missing" extent="2 pages">
                  <desc>〈2 pages missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:6695:3"/>
of his Soueraigne? Yet did Sir <hi>Carey Adoughertie</hi> in the heigth of his prowd ouer-weening, thinke that like a whirle-winde hee ſhould throw downe all that with-ſtood his furie, and that like a ſtorme at Sea, the whole kingdome of Ireland ſhould vaile to him, to ſaue it ſelfe from ſhipwrack. But God, whoſe Angels, are the garde of Princes perſons, and whoſe right hand ſteeres the helme, by which Kingdomes are gouerned, did arme the Lord Deputie, and the Councell of Ireland, not one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lie with preſent courage to encounter this Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bell, but with wiſedome to preuent, and to beat backe all ſtormes that by his boyſterous and and turbulent ſpirits were threatned to diſqui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>et the peaceable ſtate of the country.</p>
            <p>One thouſand Engliſh are therefore forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with leuied, and thoſe diuided into three regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, vnder the conducts of theſe Gentlemen and others, <hi>viz.</hi>
               <list>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Thomas Ridgeway,</hi> Treaſurer for Ire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Richard Wingfield,</hi> Knight Marſhall of Ireland</item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Oliuer Lambert.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Richard Morriſon.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Thomas Roper.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Francis Ruſh.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Toby Cofeild.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Sir <hi>Ioſias Bodley.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:6695:3"/>And beſides theſe, diuerſe gentlemen of name, all of them, vſing their beſt pollicie, to cut off the forces of the enemy: And becauſe, they would bee ſure, that hee ſhould not eſcape out of the nettes prepared for him, thoſe three thouſand ſo diuided into three ſeuerall companies were directed to march three ſeuerall waies into the countrie, and by that meanes the Rebell, if hee durſt come in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the fielde, might bee encompaſſed and ſet vpon.</p>
            <p>Before I proceede any further, it ſhall not bee amiſſe to ſet downe one matter, as an argument, to expreſſe the confidence that Sir <hi>Cary Adough<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ertie</hi>
had in his forces, as alſo to ſhew the pride and highneſſe of his ſpirit, and that was thus.</p>
            <p>The Biſhoppe of Derry and of thoſe parts of the country had his wife ſurprized by Sir <hi>Carry</hi> &amp; his accomplices, and by them held priſoner: no intreaty of the biſhop, no nor the ranſome of a thouſand pound (which hee offred) could buy her out of their hands wherevpon the biſhop (who freely paſſed too &amp; fro, aſwel to Sir <hi>Cary</hi> as to the Engliſh that were his friends, without diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turbance, becauſe he was a church-man) entred into ſpeech with the rebell, about his vnnaturall (proceedings againſt the peace of his country. But <hi>Adougherty</hi> being careles of his reprehenſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, in the end ſpake thus. I vnderſtand) quoth he)
<gap reason="missing" extent="2 pages">
                  <desc>〈2 pages missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:6695:4"/>
they fought with anſwerable courage, and an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwerable fortune; till at length, one of thoſe three companies, into which the Engliſh troopes were diuided, ſecretly keeping aloofe, came vpon the ſuddaine and vnexpected of the enemy, on the back of the Rebell, ſo that hee was roundly be ſet with death and his officers. They were like a heard of luſtie Deere encom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſed with huntſmen, and euery minute looked to heare the knell of their deaths rung forth; yet to ſhew that albeit they ſcorned life, they would not giue it away for nothing, they fought couragiouſlie, becauſe they purpoſed to ſell their bloud deerely. But (alas!) what ſtrength of man can hold out when the finger of God is held vp againſt them? God added vigor, and knitte the ſinews of the loyall Subiect, that hoe might bee of power to confound the trayte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous rebell. And that their pride might bee confounded euen in that perſon, that firſt made them faithleſſe to their countrie, and foes to their Soueraigne: heauen opened the hand of diuine vengeance, and from it ſhotte a bullet, which ſtrooke Sir <hi>Carey Adoughertie</hi> quite through the head. The wound was mortall, for with it, hee preſently fell downe and dyed; and ſo fell downe, that his hand laye directly vnder his cheeke, (his head leaning vpon it) and ſo was found ſlaine about ſome three houres after hee was ſhotte; the head beeing
<pb facs="tcp:6695:4"/>
afterwards out off from the ſhoulders by one of Sir <hi>Francis Ruſh</hi> his men, And from the field ſent to Dublin, where to ſtandeth (fixed on a pole,) o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uer the Eaſt-gate of the citey, called New-gate.</p>
            <p>In this skirmiſh were loſt on the Engliſh ſide very few; of the Iriſh many; for the leader being cut off, thoſe that were his followers in ſo diſho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt and diſhonorable an action, fainted, and felt the deſerued inſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed of the warres, ſo that in a ſhort time, they were all either ſlaine or (as chaff by a furious winde) blowne away a diſperſed to nothing. Since which defeat <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> diuerſe of the Rebels are come in of their owne accord, and daily more and more doe ſubmit themſelues to that mercy, which Sir <hi>Arthur Chicheſter</hi> (the Lord deputy) hath by proclamation offred vnto them.</p>
            <p>Thus haue I ſet downe the ouer-throwe of a man, whoſe fortunes might haue bin better, had not a turbulent &amp; reuenging ſpirit dwelt in his boſome: But as the courſe of his life was bloudy, ſo (by the iuſt doome of heauen) was the concluſion of it. God neuer ſuffers a hand that takes a pride to be embrewed in ſlaughter, to ſcape vnpuniſhed. Note the ends of all ſuch mutinous and barbarous-minded Rebels, that haue burn<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> vp their country with the fires of ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uill vproares, and haue layd waſt the hopes of the poore hus-bandman, and you ſhall ſee that their deathes haue beene a ſuddaine, as bloudy,
<gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:6695:5"/>
               <hi>knowne, ſuch forces as Ireland then had of the kings, were with ſome indifferent expedition made ready, and committed to the lending of the Marſhall Sir</hi> Richard Winckfield, <hi>and Sir</hi> Oliuer Lambert, <hi>the whole number amounting to</hi> 600. <hi>or there about<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> who paſsing to the</hi> Derrie <hi>without hearing of the rebell, made from thence to</hi> Culmore, <hi>a Forte ſome foure mile form it, which he had take from Captaine</hi> Harry Hart <hi>by treacherie before which was quit by thoſe that kept it for the rebel, before our for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſit downe before it, ſo that it was got with as much caſe as loſt, though more honorably: for</hi> O Dogher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie <hi>being Captaine</hi> Harts <hi>goſsip had vnder colour of friendſhip inuited him and his wife to his houſe (as he had often done before) and hauing him there, kept him priſoner, and ſwore to his wife vnleſſe ſhe would vſe ſome meanes to deceiue the warders, and deliuer him the Caſtle, her husbands life ſhould anſwer for it, which to ſaue ſhe performed the night before the</hi> Derry <hi>was burnt. This Caſtle our forces, hauing a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine gotten, they marched after him, to fight with him if he would endure, where they vnderſtood hee was: but hee hauing no ſuch purpoſe, quit his owne country, and went into</hi> Mack Swines, <hi>being place of more faſtneſſe. His wife, ſiſter &amp; daughter he had left in his country in a ſtrong caſtle of his owne, whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther after his flight our forces kept their courſe, and hauing ſummond it &amp; receau'd a peremptori anſwer fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> the Conſtable thereof they brought a peece of Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance before it, from which the ſhot being made, &amp; an offer of an aſſault giuen, did ſo daunt the defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants,
<pb facs="tcp:6695:5"/>
that they yeelded both the caſtle and companie in it to the Kings mercy, where the Biſhop of</hi> Derry <hi>(a moſt valia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t &amp; worthy Prelate) recouered his wife ſo long deteined by the rebels, and for whoſe ranſome he had a few dayes before proferd</hi> 500. <hi>pound, which was refuſed</hi> O Dogherties <hi>Lady, ſiſter &amp; daughter being an infant, were with ſome others ſent to the Caſtle of</hi> Dublin <hi>where they yet remaine. After this blow giuen him, his Kernes ſeeing their hope periſh, earneſtly preſt him to do ſomthing againſt the kings forces, or there vowd to leaue him, which he vnder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tooke to do. This being concluded, they appointed to ſet vpon our men at the edge of a wood, as they ſhould paſſe (going the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to beſiege Doe caſtle which he held) &amp; there to cut off ſome of our forces. But notice being giuen, they found a hote welcome. Whe<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               </hi> O Dogherty <hi>(hauing valor fitting a better man) thought to doe ſomthing worthy himſelfe, and therefore cauſed his foſter father</hi> Phelim Reugh <hi>to lead a wing of ſhot, and himſelfe came vp in the reare, which was well performed, but in the going off, he being ſomthing to buſie in ſhaking his Pike in a vaine floriſh, was by a ſoldier of ſir</hi> Francis Ruſh <hi>his co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>pany noted (though not for him) and ſhotte through the head:</hi> Phelim Reuhg <hi>ſeeing him fall, wheeled back and beſtrid the body, thinking to recouer it, which made the ſoldier geſſe him to be a man of ſpeciall note that was ſlaine, and therfore (being not ſo ſodainly able to charge his Peece againe) hee put powder into his panne, and made a falſe proffer, which</hi> Reugh <hi>perceiuing, and fearing the like fortune, left the body and fledde, vppon which accident our men aduanced forward,</hi>
            </p>
            <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
            </gap>
            <pb facs="tcp:6695:6"/>
            <p>that none of them do preſume to relieue, en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertaine, receiue, or protect any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons whatſoeuer, who hath beene Actors, Councellors, and Followers of the ſaid <hi>O Doghertie</hi> in his late Action of rebellion, vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on pains to bee reynted and a iudged trai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors in as higher degree as the ſayd <hi>O Dog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hertie</hi> himſelfe, or any his Adherents. Not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding We doe promiſe, that whoſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>euer ſhall deliuer or bring vnto vs the Lord Deputy, or any his Maieſties principall Commanders or Officers of his Armie, the body or bodies of any perſon or perſons, dead or aliue, who haue been followers of the ſaid <hi>O Doghertie</hi> in his ſayd rebellion, beeing Sword-men or Owners of Goods or Creathes, ſhall haue for his reward, not onely his Maieſties gratious pardon, but alſo all the goods of ſuch perſon or perſons whom hee ſhall ſo deliuer or bring vnto vs (<hi>Phelim Reough mac Dauid,</hi> and <hi>Shane mac Manus oge</hi> onely excepted) who muſt expect, no pardon, but whoſoeuer ſhall bring the ſaid <hi>Phelims</hi> head, or deliuer his body aliue, ſhall haue the full benefit of our former Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation in that behalfe.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at <hi>Dundalke</hi> 
                  <date>the vii of Iuly, 1608.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <closer>God ſaue the King.</closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:6695:6"/>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Thomas Dublin Canc.</item>
                     <item>H. Winche.</item>
                     <item>Henry Harrington.</item>
                     <item>Richard Morriſon.</item>
                     <item>Adam Loftus.</item>
                     <item>Thom. Ridgeway.</item>
                     <item>Oliuer St. Iohn.</item>
                     <item>Geff. Fenton.</item>
                     <item>H. Power.</item>
                     <item>Rich. Cooke.</item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>DVBLIN</hi>
Printed by <hi>Iohn Franckton,</hi> Printer to the Kings moſt excellent Maieſtie. 1608.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
